- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- Siklab! Siklab! Siklab!
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- Siklab! Siklab! Siklab!
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
Siklab-ers!
Are you ready?
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Because of all of you,
this is now...
the number one song
in the Philippines!
Thank you so much. Let's go!
[SIKLAB PERFORMING
"THIS IS MY VOICE"]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Stayed quiet in the corner
of the room.
Listening as everyone else
broke through.
Every voice was loud
and clear.
While I kept my words beneath
the sound.
Tried so hard to follow
every wave.
Singing lines that never
felt like mine.
Until my heart got tired
of pretending.
Like I was someone else again.
This is my voice,
shaking but it's honest.
It's honest,
I don't need to change it,
just to make them want it.
And even if I fall...
this is my voice.
Siklab! Siklab!
[AUDIENCE SHOUTING]
This is my voice.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- Siklab! Siklab!
[OVERLAPPING SHOUTING]
Miguel! Miguel!
Miguel!
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
Bye.
Bye. Bye, guys!
- Miguel!
- Bye, everyone.
[OVERLAPPING SHOUTING]
Are you sure about this, Miguel?
You're going to busk in public?
What if someone recognizes you?
Don't worry, Bro.
No one will recognize me.
I'll just modulate my voice
so no one will recognize me.
I just want to sing again
without being mobbed.
If you get caught,
you're in trouble.
Seriously, Miguel.
And your dad is definitely
going to be furious.
Whatever.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
[SOFT MUSIC]
Oh no, the curry spilled
in my bag!
And this is my favorite bag!
Sorry, I'm sorry.
Hey, get back here!
Hey, teddy bear!
Never knew a name could be.
A melody that follows me.
[MIGUEL SINGING
"IKAW LANG (WHAT I CAN'T SAY)"]
Feelings inside my chest...
rising up to my throat.
If I say it out loud,
will you even listen?
Finally, I caught you,
you troublemaking teddy bear.
You're the one who spilled
chicken curry on my bag.
For your information,
curcumin in curry can chemically
bind to fabric fibers.
Look, the stain won't come out.
Miss!
What was that?
The song was already beautiful,
and then you had to ruin it.
Miss, I'm really sorry.
Let's talk later.
I promise, after my set.
I'm sorry.
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[QUIRKY MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'm sorry I ran off
when I stained your bag.
Here.
I got you a new one.
It's the same brand, but they
didn't have it in white anymore.
So, I hope you like blue.
Go on, take it.
Come on, so teddy bear won't be
sad anymore.
Here, take it.
Please.
Don't be mad anymore.
Wait.
How did you buy this
when you were busking earlier?
I had my PA buy it.
I mean, I asked a friend
to get it.
[GENTLE MUSIC]
Please don't be mad
at me anymore.
I'm really sorry.
Friends?
Fine.
Friends.
Go on, open it.
Do you approve?
Thank you.
[GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Every Friday...
he sings at Manila Park.
He never told me
who he really was.
He said it was a secret.
All I know is that
we're the same age.
If only...
So, I gave him a nickname.
"Captain Serenade,"
because he always wears
that captain-style cap.
the things...
you helped me get through.
And he sings so beautifully.
Wanted to stop dreaming.
You gave me something I want
to hold on to.
I'd tell you I'm sorry.
Bet you thought you knew me well
I hope you felt the two words.
I couldn't say to you...
I love you.
But one day...
we suddenly stopped seeing each
other.
[POIGNANT MUSIC]
This next song is also
an original
and I wrote it for someone
who isn't here.
Feelings inside my chest...
rising up to my throat.
If I say it out loud.
Will you listen to me?
Or should I just keep my mouth
shut?
My crooked smile trembles
with nerves.
My lips are dry,
aching with longing.
I can't say it.
I just can't say it
Cause baby,
you are my favorite song.
I'll put you on repeat
all night.
I know I'll never move on.
My first, right where I belong.
You are my first heartbeat song.
[MELLOW MUSIC]
I never made it back
to Manila Park.
Based on the results,
Sir has pancreatic cancer.
My grandfather was diagnosed
with stage 3 pancreatic cancer.
The doctor said he only had
about a year left to live.
But Grandfather Xavi refused
chemotherapy...
no matter how much we begged
him.
I'm not going through treatment
anymore.
It's just a waste of money.
- Dad.
- Grandfather, please.
We can ask politicians for help.
What?
They're the ones stealing
from us.
And you'd trade my dignity
just to get their help?
No.
You know...
all I really want is this...
I don't want you to struggle
or be more stressed.
Okay?
Most of all...
I don't want to leave you
with nothing.
I hope you understand that.
I'm already old.
I'm ready to meet the Lord.
Do you think everything you
cooked today will be finished?
Mama Bebe, Grandfather Xavi.
What?
- Surprise!
- Wow!
So even though it hurt,
Grandfather Xavi and I went
ahead with his bucket list.
Are you ready for
"Grandpa Xavi's Bucket List"?
It's a list of things he wants
to do before he's gone.
"Put a medal on A..."
Of course.
That's what we've always been
hoping for, right?
Of course.
You promise, right?
- That's a promise.
- We'll make that happen.
Ah, okay.
Are you ready for the next one?
So, what's next?
Next.
"Go to..."
- Dad, really.
- Me?
Really? With...
How did you know?
- Of course I know that.
- Dad is clearly very excited.
- Very excited.
- I think I'd like that.
- Okay. Next.
- All right.
Let's go to number four first.
Number four...
Hey, I like that too...
- to travel...
- To go swimming.
I've always wanted to see
resorts like that.
- Yes, the white sand beaches.
- I could learn a lot from that.
Dad, they say it's really
beautiful.
- Yes, we'll go there.
- I'm so excited.
- White sand.
- Yes.
- The white sands of Boracay.
Number five...
"Find a partner for..."
Dad, you really went there.
You even dragged me into this.
- Unbelievable.
- He's just reading my mind.
- Oh my.
- I'm not saying anything...
but if there's a chance...
All right, if there's a chance.
That's your challenge.
Let's see about that, Mama Bebe.
Oh, what could this be?
- Okay, what's number one?
- This is the grand finale.
Number one,
this is the most important.
"To build..."
Yes.
And number one on Grandfather
Xavi's list...
is to build and make successful
the dream resort
he and Grandmother Marie always
wanted,
before they meet again
in heaven.
I hope we can make all of that
come true.
We'll make it happen, Dad.
Thank you, my grandchild.
Oh my.
If we manage to do all that...
your grandmother will be
so happy.
Come on, have some turon
for snacks.
- Thank you, Mama Bebe.
- It's ready.
You know...
we were so happy that day.
Have it with some leche flan.
While we were laughing,
even just for a moment...
we forgot all our problems.
Is it good, Dad?
Where's the jackfruit?
I mixed in leche flan instead.
It has leche flan inside.
That's my specialty.
No wonder it's all gone.
Yes, but if you want more,
you can have some.
You're probably wondering,
how someone like me
could build a resort.
Good thing I'm not like other
16-year-olds,
because my IQ is 156.
That's considered genius level,
according to studies.
And to make Grandfather Xavi's
dream come true...
I studied everything
about building a resort.
Mm.
- Have some milk tea first.
- Thank you, Grandfather.
But I realized intelligence
alone isn't enough...
because we're not rich.
I'm getting sleepy.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Don't stay up too late.
- Yes.
- Get some rest.
Thank you, Grandfather.
- Good night.
I had to be resourceful
to build our dream resort.
["YOU ARE MY FAVORITE SONG"
BY PRINCESS ALIYAH]
We sold everything
we had in Manila...
so we could move to...
Solmera City.
It's three hours away
from Manila
and it's similar to Cebu City.
It's modern,
but it has beautiful beaches.
You are my favorite song
You're my first hello to love
My first, right where I belong.
That's where the beach property
Grandmother left us is located.
It was pawned when she got sick
and passed away.
But Grandfather Xavi
was able to reclaim it
using his retirement pay
from the government.
[WAVES LAPPING]
- Come on, my grandchild.
- Okay.
- Look at that.
- [ANGEL CHUCKLES]
- See? Isn't it beautiful?
- Come on, Grandfather Xavi.
Look at that.
- Hurry up.
- It's so beautiful.
You know, a sunset
only lasts a moment.
- [ANGEL AND BEBE LAUGH]
- It doesn't last long,
but it's incredibly beautiful.
- Oh, Dad.
- All right.
- Easy now.
- Aww.
Look, look.
That's all ours.
[BEBE EXHALES]
When your grandmother
and I got this property...
we never let it go.
So many people tried
to buy it from us,
but we never accepted
any of their offers.
Even when we made a mistake
and pawned it,
as soon as I received
my retirement pay,
I redeemed it right away.
This is where you'll see
the most beautiful sunset
in all of Solmera City.
[CHUCKLES]
After all the years
we've held onto this,
so many people have tried
to buy it.
- But, Dad, do you think...
-[ANGEL EXHALES]
your remaining retirement money
will be enough
and what little I've saved
from selling turon
to build our resort?
The resorts we passed
by were all so beautiful,
especially that Monta...
Montaverde Group of Hotels.
It has such a nice name, right?
The owner must be a billionaire.
- Maybe.
- Oh my.
But we don't have to compete
with them, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- We can do this, Mom Bebe.
I've already calculated
Grandfather Xavi's remaining
money.
So if we start with three
starter villas,
at 180,000 pesos each,
using light materials
and basic finishes,
then 150,000 pesos will go
to permits and utilities.
And the remaining 205,000 pesos
will cover initial operations
and staff salaries.
So if our monthly expenses
are 60,000 pesos
and we charge 3,500 pesos
per night
with a 50 percent
occupancy rate,
that gives us a monthly gross
of 150,000 pesos,
we'll break even in about seven
to eight months.
So it's possible we'll see
a full return within the year.
There's also a big chance
we could lose money,
but as long as occupancy
doesn't drop below 20 percent,
we'll manage.
[XAVI AND ANGEL LAUGH]
- [BEBE EXHALES SHARPLY]
- [LAUGHTER]
- [LAUGHS]
- So, Dad?
Ah, where did all that
come from?
I didn't understand
what you said,
- my dear, but...
- Oh, Grandfather Xavi.
But the way you said it...
it sounded convincing.
You're right, my dear.
We can do this.
- [ANGEL LAUGHS]
- What?
Me, I'll just say this...
- group hug!
- Group hug!
["YOU'RE MY FAVORITE SONG"
BY PRINCESS ALIYAH]
The next three months
weren't easy.
We did everything
to finish the resort.
We poured all the money
we had into it.
You are my favorite song
- [ZION GROANS]
- I'm not beating you up.
I just need a scratch paper.
- Is that an equation?
- Thank you
for being a sacrifice.
There, write on that.
Go on.
- [DASH CHUCKLES]
- [ZION GROANS]
Calix, please.
The bell's about to ring,
ma'am is coming.
- Scratch paper.
- Yo, Calix.
What if we write on his glasses
instead?
- Yeah, Bro.
- Excuse me.
- Let me see.
- Excuse me!
Hey, what are you doing to him?
Stop it.
- [CHUCKLING]
- Who is this?
And who the hell are you?
[SOFT TENSE MUSIC]
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, wait.
Let me guess.
You're the new junior high
transferee.
- Ahh. That's her.
- Right?
Oh.
Yes, that's me.
It's 2026, and bullying
is still the best
your brain cells can do?
You hurt others
just to look tough.
But the truth is,
you're nothing.
Hey, man, Calix.
- She's got guts.
- You're pretty bold.
Yo, Miss Transferee,
for your information,
Calix is the smartest student
here at Brighton Bay Academy,
okay?
No one can beat him
academically, okay?
Know your place.
- As if.
- [TENSE MUSIC]
I just wanted to busk here.
I was just hoping, Jacob.
That Angel might be here
at Manila Park
since this is where you met
before?
[ENGINE REVS]
You've got a lot of energy.
Why don't you go back
to the studio,
meet up with your bandmates,
and finish your album?
Wait, who's that?
We're not even open yet.
[TENSE MUSIC]
Out of all the people
you could go up against
here at Brighton Bay Academy,
you chose me?
I'm not afraid of you, Calix.
Do it, Calix. Punch her.
- Yeah, she deserves it.
- Come on.
- Miguel.
- [CHUCKLES]
You seem distracted.
Fix yourself. Smile, engage.
They might think
you're being aloof.
- Hm?
- Yes, Dad. Sorry.
- [SQUEALING]
- Siklab! Siklab!
Siklab! Siklab! Siklab! Siklab!
["YOU'RE MY FAVORITE SONG"
BY PRINCESS ALIYAH]
- [CLAPPING]
- We were amazing.
Come on, smile.
We're in the lead.
If it's okay with you,
I can lift you up.
You seem familiar.
'Cause baby, you are
- My favorite song
- Yup. It's me, Angel.
[CHUCKLES]
You're my first hello to love
My first, right where...